André Walker - Curriculum Vitae

I'm an experienced software developer, passionate about programming since I was 13. I'm self-taught, zealous about code quality while also being pragmatic.

In my current job at Booking.com, I have lead and implemented projects to improve the development experience of hundreds of developers.

I am engaged in Open Source, with an active GitHub profile, having contributed to a variety of libraries and tools. I attend and occasionally speak at local technical events and conferences.

Work Experience

Lead Developer - Booking.com (September 2015 - present)

I was one of the creators of an internal framework which simplified the creation and maintenance of back-office applications and services. I designed its DSL, introduced tests to it (which wasn't in the company's culture at the time), and implemented many of its features. It was used by about 200 applications, serving hundreds of millions of requests per day. I implemented integrations with Kubernetes, setting up the base images and templating kubernetes configurations with Helm. I lead an initiative to restructure the legacy codebase, along with principal developers and several stakeholders, to accelerate the move to services and improve developer experience. To that end, I implemented Bazel rules for Perl and internal Booking systems, and the first draft was public on GitHub.

Software Developer - Estante Virtual (January 2014 - July 2015)

Estante Virtual is a Brazilian e-commerce with the largest collection of used books in the country. Most of my work was on the shopping cart and processing payments, and I was responsible for integrating with a new payment gateway.

Google Summer of Code (May 2011 - August 2011)

My project was "Rework Catalyst component setup code". The goal was to use Inversion of Control to make the configuration of the components more flexible and powerful in the Catalyst MVC framework. I learned a lot about how to write better tests and the importance of back-compatibility, with the help of my mentors and other developers in the project.

Skills

I have a lot of experience with Perl, having worked on frameworks and infrastructure libraries for most of my career so far. Even if the language itself is in decline, the pragmatism I learned from it has really been valuable. While I am mostly a back-end developer, I have written and maintained JavaScript code, as well as other front-end languages such as Typescript. In my free time I have also built websites with Elm, which I found extremely expressive and engaging, but challenging.

During my 3 years of technical secondary school and 4 years of university, I wrote a large amount of C, Java and even some Assembly. I have also experimented with Haskell and OCaml in my free time, and I love the strict typing and elegant solutions they provide.

I have written a good amount of rules for Bazel. I find it an invaluable tool, and I hope it keeps gaining popularity. I have a good understanding of Kubernetes and Docker. I feel comfortable deploying and debugging containerized applications, and tweaking Kubernetes configurations.

I have used extensively both MySQL and PostgreSQL for personal and commercial projects. I also had contact with Oracle and MS SQL Server in university. I use Linux exclusively for my personal computer and servers for over 15 years. I set up numerous servers for serving HTTP traffic and mail servers, and I have familiarity with AWS.

Education

- Bachelor in Computer Science, UFSCar University of São Carlos $2014\,$
- Technical degree in Informatics, COTUCA Technical High School of Campinas 2009